José Hiram Soltren

1201 West Park Street, Cedar Park, TX 78613-2801, United States

■ jsoltren@alum.mit.edu © +1 (347) 503-9558 ■ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jsoltren

Synopsis

Senior Software Engineer. MIT alum. Focus on device drivers, C/C++, Linux, AI. Broad systems and user software experience. Pilot and avionics geek. Skills: C/C++, Linux, deep learning, computer vision, 3D graphics, avionics, firmware, Apache Spark. Scala. OpenGL. hardware emulation, qdb. Fluent in Spanish.

EXPERIENCE

Founder Soltren Consulting LLC, Cedar Park, TX

Jan 2014 - Feb 2020

- Technical consulting, including software engineering and product management.
- Product manager for a product line of high-end computer keyboards.
- Avionics system design for small aircraft operating under IFR with GPS.
- Deep Learning on PyTorch and TensorFlow. Performance analytics for ResNet, SSD, YOLO, Inception, FPN, LSTM. Added hardware backend to PyTorch.
- Brought XMIT Hall Effect Mechanical Keyboard to market. Sold through!

Deep Learning Software Engineer Intel Corporation Aug 2017 - Feb 2019

- AI hardware device driver for Nervana deep learning accelerator, focusing on memory management, parallel execution, and performance.
- Algorithms for data/model/kernel parallelism across multiple chips and hosts.

Software Engineer Cloudera, Inc.

May 2016 - Aug 2017

- Contributions to Apache Spark, a distributed computation platform with fault tolerance billed as the successor to MapReduce.
- Implemented and upstreamed a blacklisting mechanism for faulty compute resources.
- Designed an addition to Apache Spark that would allow compute resources to report on memory utilization in real time.

Senior System Software Engineer NVIDIA Corporation May 2011 - Apr 2016

- Video decode and post-processing technical lead. Added H.265/HEVC decode support to VDPAU. Wrote stream parser for H.265/HEVC video streams.
- Firmware and device driver development for 2D/3D graphics on Linux hosts.
- Fixed a bug that crashed the GPU when playing back some videos.
- Fixed dozens of bugs in the NVIDIA Linux driver graphics stack.
- Served as technical mentor to several engineers over the years.
- New hardware bringup across four generations of NVIDIA GPUs.

Member of Technical Staff Model N, Inc.

Aug 2009 - Nov 2010

• New feature and bug fixing for revenue management software for pharmaceutical and semiconductor enterprise customers. Focus on customer bugs and escalations.

Systems Administrator D. E. Shaw & Co., L.P.

Jun 2007 - Jun 2008

- \bullet Helpdesk support for traders and analysts during market hours.
- Streamlined operations resulting in reduced call time and volume.
- IT projects including video teleconferencing and backup infrastructure.

EDUCATION

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA

Master of Engineering and S.B. Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

CITIZENSHIP

United States